Mss.Rec.81 Mss.Rec.81
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - White Calf's Mandan Origin Myth [1 of 2], 1969; 16-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:59:12; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.; White Calf, Frank
    Collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Frank White Calf in June 1929. This is a second re-recording of this program made from the orignal master tapes, after the first re-recording [APSdigrec_0773] was cut off before the completion of the program. This re-recording contains the entirety of the program, but is of poorer quality.
  - All Yellow's account of doctoring, 1969; 16-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:05; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--Biography; Mandan Indians--Medicine
  - Creek Medicine of Beaver, Otter, Turtle, 1969; 16-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:51; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Beavers; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Medicine; Indians of North America--North Dakota
  - Awaxawi myths of "Trying the Pot" ceremony, 1969-08; 16-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:07; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Indians of North America--North Dakota
  - Wolf Ceremony myths of Wolf Woman and Strong Jaw (to pg 415), 1969; 16-10; 1.0 .mp3; 01:05:55; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Story is continued on APSdigrec_0781.
  - Continues myth Strong Jaw to Walks at Night; Wolf Woman Ceremony, 1969; 16-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:22; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Continuation of story begun on APSdigrec_0780.
  - Annie's account (in Hidatsa) about "Walks Village" near their old home in Missouri, 1969; 16-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:25; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Indians of North America--North Dakota
  - Sunset Wolf Myth and Related Ceremony, 1969; 16-13; 1.0 .mp3; 01:39:14; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Hidatsa language; Indians of North America--North Dakota
  - Old Woman Who Never Dies, 1969; 16-14; 1.0 .mp3; 02:17:42; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Older women--Folklore
  - Stays Yellow's Doctoring, 1969-08-05; 16-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:38:05; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Indians of North America--North Dakota; Mandan Indians--History; Mandan Indians--Medicine; Mandan Indians--Social life and customs
  - Small Hawk Myth and Ceremony, 1969; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:18:10; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Hidatsa Creation Myth, 1969; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:45:10; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Creation--Mythology; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa mythology
  - Waterbuster Skull Bundle Myth [1 of 2], 1969; 17-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:58:45; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Story originally told to Alfred W. Bowers by Wolf Chief.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Hidatsa mythology
  - Waterbuster Skull Bundle Myth [2 of 2], 1969; 17-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Buffalo Neckbone Myth and Ceremonial layout of Fishhook Village in 1845, 1969; 17-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:59; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Story originally told to Alfred W. Bowers by Bear's Arm. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Arapahoan language of the same name.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--History--19th century; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs
  - Woman Above and Holy Women Myths, 1969; 17-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:35; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Collector's documentation indicates that a completion of the story was recorded, but this program was not found on the tapes transferred from collector's master copies.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa mythology; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - Myths of the Thunder, 1969; 17-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:39; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa mythology
  - Myths of Naming the Earth, 1969; 17-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:55; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Recording ends with description of collection and translation of subsequent recording. See Related Recording. Story originally told to Alfred W. Bowers by Mrs. White Duck.
  - The Myths of Swallow and Hawk, 1969; 17-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:41; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Description of the collection and translation of this story given at end of prior recording. See Related Recording. Recording cut off before completion of story.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa language; Hidatsa mythology
  - Myths of the Bear Ceremony, 1969; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:28; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Bears--Folklore; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - The Roadmaker Narrative [1 of 2], 1969; 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:02:10; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Story originally told to Alfred W. Bowers by Bear's Arm.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Biography; Hidatsa Indians--History; Warriors
  - The Roadmaker Narrative [2 of 2], 1969; 18-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:06:00; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Guts and Never Run Away Narrative, 1969; 18-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:15; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    First 3:00 consists of informal conversation. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Arapahoan language of the same name.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--History; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Warriors
  - The Red Stick Myths and Ceremony, 1969; 18-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:54; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Tape cut-off before completion of story.
    Anthropological linguistics; Buffaloes--Folklore; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - Myth of the Snow Owl [2 of 4], 1969; 18-06; 1.0 .mp3; 01:21:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Portion from 01:12:15 to end of recording consists of tape tests by collector conducted by the reading of short sections of text.
    A part 1 of 4 is indicated in collector's documentation but not found on tapes transferred from collector's master copies.
  - Census of people living in 1870 [1 of 2], 1969; 18-07; 1.0 .mp3; 02:05:10; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History--19th century; Hidatsa language; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--History--19th century; United States--Census, 9th, 1870
  - Census of people living in 1870 [2 of 2], 1969; 18-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:03; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History--19th century; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--History--19th century; United States--Census, 9th, 1870
  - Myth of the Snow Owl [3 of 4], 1969; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:14; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - Myth of the Snow Owl [4 of 4], 1969; 19-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:29; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Concludes with discussion of the end of the researcher's current round of recording sessions. A part 1 of 4 is indicated in collector's documentation but not found on tapes transferred from collector's master copies.